PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an expert Machine Learning Engineer/Artificial Intelligence Developer. I have been working on multiple real-world Deep learning projects and product development in industry. I also have deployed Deep learning/Machine learning models on the cloud environment as well as flask API. I have a great deal of experience in deep learning for Computer Vision. My expertise is in image/video classification, object detection/ tracking from image & videos, Image segmentation, Human activity detection, Anomaly Detection, Synthetic image generation, High resolution image generation.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Artificial Intelligence Engineer

CINTIQS, Ottawa, Ontario, Jan 2022 - Sep 2022

▶ I have been working on AI Innovation projects to build the whole pipeline of AI software for the military, defense industry.

Senior Machine Vision Specialist

Neatco Eng service, Kitchener, Ontario, Oct 2021 - Feb 2022

▶ Worked on industrial automation, robot vision. I have worked on training and deployment of Object detection model for core products.

Artificial Intelligence Developer

Intelense, Markham, Ontario, Jun 2020 - Sep 2021

- >> I have worked to build the whole pipeline of different ongoing projects
- ▶ I have programmed building real-time video analytics for public safety applications like anomaly detection(GAN,,WGAN, VAE), accident detection, Fall detection(pose estimation), Fight detection, Fire and smoke detection, etc
- **▶** Using real-time camera feed(RTSP, HTTP), I have integrated AI solution for public safety using Deep learning, computer vision in development platform
- ▶ I have also Improved and corrected existing software and system applications, programmed applications and tools using object-oriented languages
- ▶ I have accomplished research and development of new equipment, products and processes
- **▶** Reviewed literature to remain current with new procedures and apply learnings to related research
- **▶** Recommended improvements to facilitate team and project workflow.

Polaris Transport, Toronto, Ontario, Aug 2018 - Nov 2018

- **▶** I have worked on classification of customer email in work fusion automation process, other relevant machine learning task
- Technology used: Machine learning, Java, work fusion automation, sql, tableau reporting, mysql databases, AWS.

🖈 Data Analyst

Dutch Bangla Bank Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh, Jun 2010 - Apr 2016

➤ Conducted data mining and retrieval using Mysql to pinpoint critical business areas.My Key Achievements: Identified top customers by using clustering algorithms.

PUBLICATIONS

IEEE International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (ISBI) 2022

IEEE International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (ISBI) 2022

PATENTS

I have developed different deep learning model and optimization technique for industrial application as the company patent at Intelense Inc.

LINKS

\$\tinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/husne-jahan/

☆ Github URL: https://github.com/husnejahan

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:

4+-years of using Python(Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras), C/C++, R, SQL, MATLAB

Al Model Training:

- ► Machine Learning & Deep Learning: ANN, CNN, 3DCNN, RNN, LSTM, BLSTM, GRU, Object detection API, OpenCV, UNET, GAN, AnoGAN, CycleGAN, DCGAN, Super Resolution GAN (SRGAN), Conditional GAN (CGAN)
- **▶** Advance Computer Vision: Real-time video analytics and video mining, video processing with AI 3D object detection, Annomaly detection using GAN. Super Resolution GAN (SRGAN) to produce higher resolution images
- **▶** GPU Computing: NVIDIA GPU, CUDA, cuDNN, Keras, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Tensorboard

Al Model Deployment and Optimization:

- **▶** Deployment API: AWS Sagemaker, Flask server, REST API
- >> TensorRT, TensorflowLite for Model compression
- ➤ Machine Learning Operations (MLOps): OpenShift cluster, docker container

- **▶** Big Data Analytics: Spark-Scala, Hive, Flume, Sqoop, Pig (in Cloudera), Databricks for Spark
- **▶** Postgres SQL, MongoDB
- → Operating Systems & Tools: Mac, Windows, Linux, ROS
- ➤ Cloud: AWS (EC2, S3 bucket storage, EMR cluster, Sage maker, Lambda),Google Cloud

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning- Online Certifications

- A How Google does Machine Learning- Google Cloud Training- Issued by Coursera.
- 🖒 Launching into Machine Learning-Google Cloud Training- Issued by Coursera.
- Convolutional Neural Networks in TensorFlow- Issued by Coursera.
- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning Issued by Coursera.
- ☆ Introduction to Containers w/ Docker, Kubernetes & OpenShift- Issued by Coursera.
- Containers & Kubernetes Essentials- Issued by Coursera. Authorized by IBM

🖒 Design Thinking for Innovation- University of Virginia- Issued by Coursera

EDUCATION

PROJECTS

COMPUTER VISION

VIDEO ANALYTICS -

Master of Engineering(Electrical & Computer Eng.): Computer Engineering(Machine Learning)

Ryerson University, Toronto, ON, Jan 2019

- Anomaly detection using WGAN for Video Surveillance: Video analytics platform for public safety. Technical Scope: Python (PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras), Deep Learning, Flask API(REST), Docker, Digital Ocean, Postgres. **Key Achievements**: Improved WGAN for unsupervised learning in real-time with better accuracy.
- Achievements: The Model can detect human activity in real-time with better accuracy.

 Applied different optimization technique.
- Detecting custom objects in images/video using: Trained TF model using custom images, which can detect multiple objects. Technical Scope: Python(TensorFlow), Deep Learning, YOLOV5/V4/V3 with Darkflow for Intelligent systems. Key Achievements: Enabled model to detect an object in real time as well as detect multiple objects. The model can detect & recognize custom objects more than 98% accuracy in realtime. Optimized model 5-times less size using TFLite.
- Face detection and Face recognition: deployment with Flask API: Trained and deployed face recognition model.

Technical Scope: DLib, MTCNN, Deep Learning. **Key Achievements**: The model can detect & recognize persons face with mask and without mask in realtime camera feed.

- **Image Synthesis with Auxiliary Classifier GANs : Technical Scope: Python , Deep Learning , ACGAN, Keras. Key Achievements: Improved training of generative adversarial networks (GANs) for image synthesis.
- ☼ UNet: Convolutional Networks for Biomedical Image Segmentation: Technical Scope: Python, Deep Learning. Key Achievements: Optimized the model which can segment biomedical images with fewer processing time. Decreased model training parameters.